OFRI OREN

ofrioren@gmail.com | (310) 985 – 4692 www.linkedin.com/in/ofrioren | https://github.com/oloren0

Professional Summary

Data professional with two years of experience using data and eight years of professional experience in education. My greatest strength is taking data and making it accessible through storytelling and visuals. On the technical end, my greatest strengths are statistical analysis and Python. Understanding how to read data allows us to ask thought-provoking questions, probe the information presented to us for accuracy, and find answers.

Technical Skills

Software: Python, SQL (PostGre, My), TensorFlow, Keras, Spark and PySpark, R, STATA, Tableau, Canvas, Adobe CS (InDesign, Photoshop, Bridge), Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Google Office Suite, social media.

Projects

IDENTIFYING BRAIN TUMORS WITH MACHINE LEARNING

- · Summary: Used neural net machine learning on brain MRI scans to identify tumors.
- \cdot About: I used supervised learning to train a neural net to locate tumors in images from brain scans. I then attempted to apply this set to images without labels already identified but was unable to create sufficient pseudo-labels to retrain the images.
- · Outcome: I segmented brain images on a smaller set.
- · Technical skills: TensorFlow, Keras, Albumentation, transformed images, used image convolutions to create a neural net for segmentation and classification by location.

HOMELESSNESS IN CALIFORNIA

- · Summary: Forecast of homeless rate in California per county.
- · About: Predicted amount of homeless using timeseries data with multiple different models.
- · Technical skills: wrangling missing data, PCA, Dickey-Fuller stationarity testing, auto-correlation testing, trained and tested a linear regression model, seasonal auto-regressive model (SARIMAX) model, and a vector auto-regression (VAR) model to select the best model and hyperparameters.

DATA SCIENCE COHORT GUIDED CAPSTONE

- · Summary: Evaluated whether a hypothetical skiing company should adjust their ticket prices based on those of their competitors and whether they should add a ski lift.
- · About: Conducted a price comparison with other companies that have similar facilities. Forecast changes in revenue in multiple different scenarios including adding a new chair lift, closing a ski run, opening a new ski run, creating additional snow, or extending their longest ski run.
- · Outcome: Ultimately, I advocated adding a chair lift, depending on the cost of installation, and opening a new ski run. I argued against closing a run unless it was necessary and suggested that the company solicit feedback from customers about closures.

· Technical skills: wrangling missing data, feature engineering, PCA, trained and tested a linear regression model, created a pipeline (a standard scaler, simple imputer, and k-best features), performed cross-validation, did a hyperparameter search using GridSearch, and finally used a Random Forest model in the pipeline, with finetuned hyperparameters from cross-validation with GridSearch.

Recent Professional Experience

TUTORING

Mathematics tutor, *Tutor Me Education*, April 2024 – December 2024

- · Explained mathematical operations to elementary school students in a way that makes information memorable and accessible.
- · Challenged the more advanced students to glimpse real world applications, for example: the way prime factors can be used in cryptography.
- · Engaged students from the standpoint of their own interests to cultivate trust and inspire appreciation for learning. Taught groups of three to six students at once with more than thirty students in total.

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Teaching assistant, UC Berkeley, July 2022 – August 2022; July 2023 – December 2023

- · Made complex and abstract information accessible to university students to make ancient philosophy relevant to future scholars.
- · Talked with students to 'midwife' their ideas and feelings into argumentative structure and cogent writing, including editing their work for revision.
- · Operated professionally with students, professors, and staff to ensure that education is maintained at a university standard including providing access to instructional materials, equitable grading, and additional office hours for students. Taught as few as fifteen students to as many as sixty-five per academic term.
- · Ancient philosophy is my passion; it reorganized my value system and focused my path to gain understanding of myself in relation to the world around me.

TEACHING

Instructor of record, San Francisco State University, August 2018 – December 2018

- \cdot The Art of Quantitative Reasoning: *Las Meninas*, Philosophy, and Mathematics was a course with approximately forty students enrolled.
- · Designed a course syllabus to meet California State University learning standards and objectives for a required course.
- · Explained advanced mathematical and logical concepts including Hilbert's Paradox, Russell's Paradox, and others using art as a vehicle.
- · Taught a university course with homework, exams, extra credit, additional resources for further learning.

Education

2024 Springboard, San Francisco (Remote) – Data Science Certificate

2020 San Francisco State University, San Francisco – Master of Arts, Philosophy

2016 University of Reading, Reading, Great Britain – Master of Arts, Book Design

2011 University of California, Berkeley – Bachelor of Arts, Economics